CURRICULUM VITAE



Personal information

Surname(s) / First name(s)

Address(es)

Telephone(s)

Email(s)

Date of birth

Oprisan Andrei

str Magura, nr 24, 550317, Sibiu, jud Sibiu, Romania

+40 748 75 75 95

andrei.oprisan@obsidian-innovations.com

th | April 17, 1982

Personal skills and competences

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

Andrei has 12 years of experience in software industry and academia, acting as product manager, software developer, architect and researcher, with almost 5 years in the data security field and 3 years writing Business Intelligence SaaS applications.

Andrei's area of work led him to design and develop data destruction software solutions and Business Intelligence SaaS applications, handle a variety of technical tasks ranging from back-end services architecture and implementation to developing front-end GUIs. Deep work in back-end services made him a Guru on integration strategies with different third party service providers. While working in data security area he was involved in the achievement of industry top security certificates.

In the last several years Andrei has been consulting companies and startups on software development services.

Additional information can be found in his LinkedIn profile

http://www.linkedin.com/in/aoprisan

Romanian

English (advanced)

MOTHER TONGUE
OTHER LANGUAGES

Key projects and accomplishments

DRESSPANIC, 2014

http://www.dresspanic.com

Designed and developed the concept and implementation of a web application with the social network and marketplace aspects for fashion followers, stylists and other "what to wear" female questioners. Scala, Play 2, JavaScript, Amazon S3, MongoDB, Loginza, Tradedoubler.

ForestryCloud, 2014

http://www.forestrycloud.com

Designed and developed the concept and implementation of a web application for online forest inventory system. Scala, Play 2, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, GeoServer, OpenLayers, Paytrail. Mobile app with restricted features using Titanium by Appcelerator.

Sмееві, 2013

http://www.smeebi.com

Designed and developed the concept and implementation of a complex business intelligence web application. Details provided below.

SCALAEX MUSIC DLAVED 2013

https://github.com/ssemakin/scfx-player

A maturity test for the JavaFX 2.x based ScalaFX framework.

http://www.thrive-reporter.com/

Data visualization and reporting tool for analyzing securities markets trading activity. JavaFX 1.x, Scala, JasperReports.

http://www.obsidian-innovations.com

IT consultancy company. Team member and co-founder. Details provided below.

http://www.blancco.com/us/products/total-data-erasure/blancco-5/

Based on the experience of the prior versions, bootstrapped and developed the first releases of a new generation data destruction software solution. Details provided below.

Graduation work for my Bachelor degree, built with a team of three people, using cutting edge technologies for that date, such as Asp.Net 2.0, Ajax.Net, Dependency Injection, object relational mapping.

Additional information

Literature, jogging, hiking, traveling, programming languages

Recommendations

Rob Connell, CEO of Smeebi, +358 505 851 302

Mika Hurskainen, Chairman of Smeebi, +358 40 7576 713

Lasse Riekkinen, Director of R&D at Blancco, +358 50 4956 615

Mikko Koponen, COO at Blancco, +358 40 6879 505

Simo Juvaste, Deputy Head of CS Department, +358 50 380 3416

Education

September 2006-September 2008

Master of Science in Computer Science

Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Science, University of Joensuu, Joensuu, Finland «Aspect Oriented Implementation of Design Patterns using Metadata »

ftp://cs.joensuu.fi/pub/Theses/2008_MSc_Oprisan_Andrei.pdf

Diploma Engineer, Computer Engineering September 2001-June 2006

Universitatea Tehnică "Gh. Asachi" din Iasi

«Web-based E-Learning platform»

Work experience

Occupation or position held

Dates

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

Main activities and responsibilities

DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD

DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

Type of rusiness or sector

Software Architect and CTO, Co-Founder

December 2011-Present Time

Smeebi Ltd (subsidiary of Olapcon Oy), Espoo and Joensuu, Finland

Software Development of Business Intelligence Systems

- Software project management, design and development using agile techniques, functional and object-oriented programming
- Technologies evaluation and business development
- Back-end architecture and development
- Integration strategies with different service providers: REST and SOAP WS, OAuth 1.0a and 2.0, JSON and XML
- Working with remote teams
- Test Driven Development: Specs2
- OLAP cubes configuration and data transformation routines
- Development primarily with Scala, Clojure/ClojureScript, JavaScript, Postfgresql, MySql, Mondrian, MDX, Play 2, SBT, Github, Heroku on GNU/Linux, Windows 7

Technical Consultant

December 2011-Present Time

Obsidian Innovations Ltd., Espoo, Finland

Software Development and Consultancy

- Design and development of a financial analysis application
- Technology evaluation, business development, project planning
- Back-end architecture and development
- Developing dashboards and reports for daily trading
- Object-oriented programming, functional programming, software architecture, Test Driven Development, web development, cloud computing
- Development primarily with Scala, JavaFX, Java, Clojure, JavaScript, Maven, Play 2, JasperReports, Talend ETL, SBT, Github on GNU/Linux, Windows 7

Technical Product Manager

March 2011-December 2011

Blancco Ltd., Helsinki and Joensuu, Finland

Development, distribution and maintenance of data destruction software systems

- Development of data destruction application
- Involvement in the gain of Data Security top certificates
- Working with remote development teams
- Development primarily with C++, Qt framework, GNU tool-chain, SVN, Trac

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD Dates

Main activities and responsibilities

Senior Software Engineer / Software Engineer

June 2007-February 2011

- Blancco Data Cleaner design and development
- Design and development of data destruction application (hardware communication, data destruction engine, remote API, graphical user interface)
- Object-oriented programming, architecture design, Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration
- Agile development using Scrum
- Enabling the adoption of Test Driven Development practices in the company
- Bringing latest industry trends in the product development process
- Working with remote development teams
- Development primarily with C, CVS, GNU tool-chain, Valgrind, Bash, Emacs, Linux Kernel 2.4-2.6, C++, Qt framework, GNU tool-chain, SVN, Trac

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD
DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

MAIN ACTIVITIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Software Engineer

March 2007-May 2007

Speech and Image Processing Unit, Computer Science and Statistics Department, University of Joensuu, Finland

Development of a speech recognition application

- GUI development for a speech recognition application
- Object-oriented programming, architecture design
- Integration of different components
- Development primarily with C++, wxWidgets, SVN